迈克 · 诺斯: 这是另一个非常非常重要的部分
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So this is another very,
very important section in terms of
形成了正确的打字稿工作方式的心理模型。
forming the right mental model
about how TypeScript works.
我给这个声明命名为合并，但是这个我们会看很多,
And I've titled the declaration merging,
but this we're gonna look a lot,
深入研究 Visual Studio 代码的工具提示如何为我们提供
look deeply into how Visual Studio
codes' ToolTips provide us with
我们可以利用这些信息来判断某件东西是否有价值,
information that we can use to figure
out whether some thing's of value,
不管是什么类型的东西。
whether some thing's a type.
迈克 · 诺斯: 另外，这有助于我们理解如何放少量
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Additionally, this helps
us understand how we can put put little
修复了顶部的库或不完美的类型信息，或
fixes on top of libraries or
imperfect type information, or
也许你想要一个还不存在的原型。
maybe you want to prototype something and
types don't exist for it yet.
这可以帮助您增加应用程序中的一些现有类型信息。
This helps you augment some of
the existing type information in your app.
让我们来看一下音符的第八部分。
So let's look at Section 8 of the notes.
在打字稿应用程序中，标识符就是
&gt;&gt; Mike North: In TypeScript app,
identifiers and just think of these as
你可以导出的东西，内部类型脚本来调用这些符号。
things that you could export, internally
types script to call these symbols.
标识符最多可以与三个东西相关联。
Identifiers can be associated
with up to three things.
值、类型或命名空间。
A value, a type or namespace.
这是一个我们还没有讨论过的名称空间，但是在
A namespace we haven't talked about yet,
but it's pretty simple in
它有点像一个对象，它有一个类型和一个值。
that it's sort of like an object in
that it has a type and it has a value.
所以在这种情况下我们可以做 baz.biz。
So in this situation we could do baz.biz.
它只是一个集合，所有的东西都融合在一起。
It's just sort of a collection
of stuff all merged together.
本身不值得报道，而且
Not really worth covering on its own, and
作为描述事物的工具越来越不受欢迎。
increasingly less popular as
a tool to describe things.
所以我要向你们展示如何给出一个符号,
So I'm gonna show you how, given a symbol,
你可以测试它是否可以作为一种类型。
you can test whether it
can be used as a type.
我们已经这样做了。
And we've already been doing this.
对不起，我们要先测试一个值，这是非常直观的。
Sorry, we're gonna test for a value first,
and this is very intuitive.
你应该能够完成某种任务。
You should be able to complete
an assignment of some sort.
如果它是一个值，变量应该能够保存它。
If it's a value,
a variable should be able to hold it.
如果你在这里得到一个类型错误，有些事情是错误的。
If you get a type error here,
something is wrong.
让我们用接口来试试。
Let's try it with the interface.
迈克 · 诺斯: 不好。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: No good.
Bar 只是指一个类型，但是它在这里被用作一个值，所以
Bar only refers to a type but
it's used as a value here, so
这是一个有效的测试，看看是否是一个值。
this is an effective test to
see if something is a value.
如何测试某物是否是一种类型？
How to test if something is a type?
尝试使用它作为一个类型，尝试使用它在左手边的一个等于，或如果
Try to use it as a type, try to use it on
the left-hand side of an equals, or if
这是一个你甚至不需要做的左手动作
it's a left you don't even have to do that
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So
如果你能成功地做到这一点，酒吧可以被视为类型。
if you can do that successfully,
bar can be regarded as type.
要测试某物是否与名称空间相关联,
To test whether something is
associated with a namespace,
你得依靠工具提示才能做到。
you're gonna have to rely on ToolTips for
that.
迈克 · 诺斯: 请注意，这三样东西都是重要的
&gt;&gt; Mike North: And just note that all
three of these things are importable and
可出口的。
exportable.
这就是我们的界面。
There's our interface.
这就是我们的价值，迈克 · 诺斯: 这就是我们的名称空间。
There's our value,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: And there's our namespace.
所以现在我们有了一些可以应用的测试,
So now, we kind of have the tests
we can apply to things,
搞清楚到底发生了什么。
to figure out what's going on.
所以函数和变量，它们是纯粹的值。
So functions and variables,
they are purely values.
只能使用类型查询提取值的类型。
You can only extract the type
of a value using a type query.
界面只是类型。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Interfaces are only types.
如果我们想在这里完成任务,
If we try to complete an assignment here,
我们得到了同样的错误，我们看到了上面。
we get the same error
we were seeing above.
地址只是指一种类型，并在这里作为一个值使用。
Address only refers to a type, and
is being used as a value here.
这就是有趣的地方,
Classes, this is where
things get interesting,
它们通过了值测试和类型测试，这就是现在的情况。
they pass both the value and the type
tests, and here's what is going on.
一方面，类是生成实例的工厂，对吗？
On one hand, a class is a factory
to produce instances, right?
它有一个构造函数。
It has a constructor.
它有一个原型。
It has a prototype.
最近我认为 JavaScript，你现在甚至可以做到这一点。
Recently I think JavaScript,
you can even do this now.
迈克 · 诺斯: 我们可以有静态成员，对吗？
&gt;&gt; Mike North: We can have static members,
right?
我们可以在课堂上直接访问这个。
Where we can access this
right off of the class.
Mike North: 所以这些都与实例的工厂有关。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So this is all associated
with the factory of instances.
另一方面，使用这个作为类型
On the other hand, using this as a type
描述了实例本身。
describes the instances themselves.
它几乎可以用作实例的接口。
It can be used as almost like
an interface for the instance.
所以我们可以看到这个符号接触工程在这两个位置。
So we can see this symbol
contact works in both positions.
在这里我们可以捕捉到类本身。
Up here we can capture the class itself.
在这里我们可以把它当作一种类型。
Down here we can use it as a type.
所以它几乎占据了两个位置。
So it kind of occupies both slots.
迈克 · 诺斯: 当声明有相同的名字时，他们似乎都堆在最上面
&gt;&gt; Mike North: When declarations have
the same name they kinda all stack on top
如果你把事情安排得恰到好处,
of each other, and
if you arrange things just the right way,
主要是你没有与其他价值观相冲突的价值观。
mainly you don't have values
that collide with other values.
你可以得到这样的东西,
You can end up with something
that looks like this,
当我们导出相册的时候，看看这个工具提示,
where when we export album,
and look at this tool tip,
这是一个值、一个类型和一个名称空间,
this is a value, a type, and a namespace,
都堆在一起，都在同一个标志上。
all stacked on top of each other,
all riding along on the same symbol.
这里就是,
This is where,
比如我不希望你掩盖工具提示中的信息。
like I don't want you to gloss over
the information in your ToolTips.
这告诉你很多，这告诉你，它是一个类，有一个接口
This tells you a lot, this tells you,
it's a class, there's an interface
使用相同的名称扩展该类，并且有一个名称空间。
of the same name that augments that
class and there's a namespace.
所以我们可以通过这里的类型测试，也就是说，我们甚至不需要
So we could pass the type test here and
that is to, we wouldn't even need
接口为了做到这一点，因为类有一个类型本身。
the interface in order to do that cuz
the class has a type in and of itself.
接口只是在类的顶部合并，并且
The interface just merges
on top of the class, and
这意味着如果我们有另一张专辑，一张新专辑,
that means that if we had
another album here, a new album,
然后是 al2点，我们可以看到界面添加了这个属性艺术家。
and then al2 dot, we can see that the
interface has added this property artist.
如果有人忘记了，这就是你要做的
This is what you do is if
someone has forgotten t
为库添加类型信息。
add something in type information for
a library.
你可以通过一个接口堆栈在那之上，并且
You could through an interface
kind of stack on top of that, and
它通过你的整个应用程序在全球范围内应用。
it applies globally
through your entire app.
所以类型信息只有一个存放范围。
So there's only sort of one scope for
where type information is held.
它不是以单个模块为基础的，它是整个应用程序的整体。
It's not on a per module basis,
it is holistically throughout the app.
演讲者2: 即使没有进口或出口？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Even without importing or
exporting it?
迈克 · 诺斯: 即使不进口也不出口，那是什么？
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Even without importing or
exporting, what is that?
扬声器2: 如果你在你的级别做一个覆盖，但是
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: If you do
an override in your level, but
你是从外面引进来的，你是说它还在使用？
you imported from outside somewhere,
you're saying it's still appwide?
迈克 · 诺斯: 是的，你所做的修改将在全世界范围内发生。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Yes, the modification
you make will happen appwide.
这很重要，因为你可能想让你所有的
And this is important because
you might wanna make all of your
在一个文件中进行修改，然后在其他地方进行修改。
modifications in one file, and
then have that, take a fact elsewhere.
有些东西，比如全局变量的类型，会非常不方便
There are certain things like types for
globals, that would be really inconvenient
试图进口和再出口，因为没有这个概念。
to try to import and re-export
because there's no concept of that.
或者 Mocha 的好例子，它会在里面描述,
Good examples that would jQuery or
Mocha, which it makes describe in it,
这些是全局函数，不需要专门导入。
those are global functions that you
don't have to exclusively import.
迈克 · 诺斯: 所以名称空间，它们有自己的位置，我们可以
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So namespaces, they have
kind of their own spot in that we can
在这个工具提示中，名称空间既不是类也不是接口，对吗？
see on this ToolTip a namespace is
neither a class nor an interface, right?
这是它自己的东西，也是这个东西出口的一部分。
It's its own thing and
it's part of this thing being exported.
它们可以与类或函数合并。
They can be merged with classes or
functions.
这是一个类的例子，我们可以看到我们有地址簿。
So here's an example of a class where
we can see we've got address book.
我们在这里所做的，相当于
And what we're doing here,
this is equivalent to what some
语言可以称之为内部类,
languages would call an inner
class where you've got sort of,
你有一个相对于父类的名称空间的类。
you have a class that is namespace
with respect to a parent class.
所以当我们呼叫我们的新用户时，我们必须说 addressBook.ABContact。
So when we call our new,
we're having to say addressBook.ABContact.
Mike North: 之所以允许这样做是因为名称空间的作用
&gt;&gt; Mike North: The reason that this is
allowed is because a namespace serves
把东西粘在什么东西上，对吗？
to sort of tack things onto something,
right?
它只是把 AB 联系人加到了通讯录上。
It's just tacking AB
contact onto address book.
这里没有模棱两可的语法。
And there's not ambiguous syntax here.
地址簿是唯一可以被调用的东西，对吗？
Address book is only something
that can be invoked, right?
因为构造函数是一个函数。
Cuz the constructor is a function.
所以如果我们引入一个碰撞，我们就会遇到这样的问题。
So if we were to introduce a collision,
we'd run into problems like this.
所以现在我们有两件事。
So now we've got two things.
比如 addressbook.ABContact。
Like addressbook.ABContact.
是一根绳子吗？
Is it a string?
这是一门课吗？
Is it a class?
有些事情需要解决。
Something's got to get resolved here.
但是它很大程度上是这个类的静态的一面。
But it like, it is largely
the static side of this class.
类似地，因为它与类一起工作，我们可以期待它会
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Similarly, because it works
with classes, we can expect that it will
函数和类只是函数，对吗？
work for functions and
classes are just functions, right?
他们是工厂。
They're factories.
我们使用 new 关键字来调用类。
We invoke classes by
using the new keyword.
同样的，我们也可以这样使用格式。
And so
similarly we can use format this way.
但是我们也储存了这种内部格式的货币，对吗。
But we've also stored this currency
which is used inside format, right?.
所以它可以引用这里的名称空间。
So it can kind of reference
the namespace here.
这里没有碰撞。
And there is no collision here.
我们可以调用函数或者
We either invoke the function or
我们使用一些附加在函数上的东西。
we use some of these things that
we've tacked onto the function.
迈克 · 诺斯: 我想让你从我的精神世界中吸取一些东西
&gt;&gt; Mike North: In terms of the things I
want you to takeaway with from my mental
模特的视角，知道什么是类型
model perspective,
knowing what's the type and
知道它的价值，会让你走很长的路。
knowing what's the value,
will take you a long way.
知道什么可以增强界面和知道什么
And knowing what can be augmented
interfaces versus knowing what
你有点必须离开时，他们的类型定义，值。
you kinda have to leave alone when
their defined in types, values.
因此，一旦你有了一个很难的值，你就不能覆盖它，因为
So once you have a value like it's hard,
you can't overwrite that because that
当接口是公平的竞争对手时，它会与 JavaScript 的行为方式发生冲突。
would conflict with the way JavaScript
behaves, when interfaces are fair game.